americancampus.com 2019-06-26

# Student Housing & Student Apartments - Privacy Policy - American Campus Communities

## **Privacy Policy  
AMERICAN CAMPUS COMMUNITIES**

###### **Effective Date: April 12, 2019**

American Campus Communities, Inc. (“American Campus Communities,” “ACC,” “we,” “us,” or “our,”) respects the privacy of our users (“you” or “your”). This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the websites we and our affiliates, subsidiaries and related entities operate.  

  **_Privacy Policy_**  
Our goal is to provide you with an excellent customer experience. We will take reasonable measures to protect the privacy of our applicants, residents, prospective residents, and Website visitors.

  We collect personal information only for purposes that a reasonable person would consider appropriate in the circumstances. Personal information is data that can be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of the personal information that we collect, use, and share (collectively, “process”), why we process this information, and the ways in which we will protect this information.  For certain persons located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), ACC is the data controller responsible for your personal data.

  Please take a moment to become familiar with our privacy practices as described below. Our websites may contain links to other sites for organizations that are not directly affiliated with American Campus Communities.  Also, American Campus Communities may have a presence on one or more social-networking sites to which you may have access. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these sites and recommend that you review their privacy statements as they may differ from those of American Campus Communities.

  **_Personal Information We Collect Directly_**  
We receive and store any information you provide in relation to our services, such as when you submit an application, communicate with us via phone or email, participate in surveys, or provide information to your online account. 

  You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested; however, by choosing not to do so, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to any inquiries you may have.

  **Information Submitted by Applicants:** In order for one of our properties to process a lease application, applicants must provide some personally identifiable information, including:

  * ###### Applicant name

  * ###### Physical address

  * ###### E-mail address

  * ###### Telephone number

  * ###### Social security number

  * ###### Date of birth

###### This information will be used to identify and consider the applicant for residency, and to contact the resident and/or the resident’s guarantor.

  **Information Collected from Prospective Residents:** We may also request contact information from prospective residents who visit or call one of our properties. The information you submit to one of our properties may be accessed by the property, and by American Campus Communities and its affiliates in order to operate and manage the services, understand our residents and residents’ guarantors, and to develop new products and services.

  Such information may include:

  * ###### Prospective resident name

  * ###### Physical address

  * ###### E-mail address

  * ###### Telephone number

###### This information may be used to contact prospective residents, or to inform them of news or promotions.

  **Information Collected from Investors:** Our website includes certain webforms that may require personal information from current and potential investors. The information you submit in a webform will be accessed by American Campus Communities in order to provide you with more information, or to address any questions or concerns you may have. Personal information collected from current or potential investors include:

  * ###### First and last name

  * ###### Email address

  * ###### Phone number

  * ###### Job title/company

  * ###### Physical/mailing address

###### Please keep in mind, any personal information you choose to submit under the “Comments” field within our webforms will be captured as well. 

  For persons located in the EEA, we will have a lawful basis to process your personal information if:

  * ###### We need to process your information or application (including transfers to our U.S. service providers) in order to provide you with the service you have requested or to enter into a contract; or

  * ###### We have a legitimate interest for processing your data, including for data analytics, enhancing or improving our services, or identifying usage trends.

###### **_Personal Information We Collect Indirectly_**  
**IP Addresses:** We collect your IP address when you visit the websites to help us administer the websites and diagnose problems.

**First and third-party cookies:** To enable our systems to recognize your browser or device and to provide our services to you, we use cookies, web beacons and similar tracking technologies.  
A “cookie” is a small text file that a website can place on your computer’s hard drive to, for example, collect information about your activities on the site to keep your account secure, to help us enhance your experience when using our website, and to gain insight on how to better serve our website users.  
We use both first and third-party cookies on our website. First-party cookies are those set by us, whereas third-party cookies are set from a domain different from the domain of the website you are visiting for our advertising and marketing efforts. We use cookies to:

  * ###### Assist with your navigation of our website;

  * ###### Track interactions on our websites or particular features on our websites;

  * ###### Remember your site preferences (e.g., language preferences); and

  * ###### Tailor advertisements to you and provide you with a personalized marketing experience.

###### We may also use Local Shared Objects, sometimes called “flash cookies,” to store information relating to your use of our websites on your computer’s hard drive to personalize and enhance your experience.  
We also classify cookies into the following categories:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies:**  
These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be disabled.

**Analytical/Performance Cookies**  
These cookies are used to allow us to recognize and maintain a log of the number of visitors that reach our website. These cookies assist us in improving our website function in the most efficient manner possible.

**Functionality Cookies**  
These cookies are used to recognize users when they return to our website, so we can personalize content for you and remember your preferences. If you choose to disable these cookies, we will not be able to automatically set your preferences when you visit our site (e.g., your preferred language and region).

**Targeting Cookies**  
These cookies are set through our website by our advertising partners. These partners may use information obtained through their cookies about your visits to our and other websites, in combination with information about your purchases and interests in order to provide advertisements about goods and services relevant to you.

**_Exercising Choices Regarding Analytics and Advertising_**  
We may use Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics or other website providers for analytics services.  These analytics services may use cookies and other tracking technologies to help us analyze how users use our websites.  Information generated by these services (e.g., your IP address and other online data) may be transmitted to and stored by Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics and other website providers on servers in the U.S. (or elsewhere) and these website providers may use this information for purposes such as evaluating your use of our websites, compiling statistic reports on our websites' activity, and providing other services relating our websites’ activity and other Internet usage.  We only retain aggregated data from Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics.

You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Adobe Analytics by going to <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html> under the section labeled “Tell our customers not to measure your use of their websites or tailor their online ads for you.”

We may engage and work with third parties to serve advertisements on our behalf on our websites, and/or on Third Party Services, and to provide analytics about the performance of our ads.  Some information about your browsing of our websites and certain Third Party Services may be collected across time and services and shared with third parties to deliver ads and/or other content to you on our websites and certain Third Party Services.  We may receive information about Third Party Services that you have visited and use it for marketing purposes—a practice sometimes termed “(re)-targeting,” “interest-based advertising,” and “online behavioral advertising” (collectively, “Interest-based Ads”).  We may participate in online advertising networks and exchanges that display Interest-based Ads to you on Third Party Services.  These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to automatically collect information about you and your activities, such as registering a unique identifier for your device and tying that to your online activities on and off of our websites. Certain companies we work with to serve Interest-based Ads participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) AdChoices Program and may display within the ads an Advertising Option Icon for Interest-based Ads that links to an opt-out tool which allows you to exercise certain choices regarding targeting.  You can learn more about the DAA AdChoices Program at <http://www.youradchoices.com/> and its opt-out program for mobile apps at <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

In addition, certain advertising networks and exchanges we work with to serve Interest-based Ads may participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). NAI has developed a tool that allows consumers to opt out of certain Interest-based Ads delivered by NAI members' ad networks.  To learn more about opting out of such targeted advertising or to use the NAI tool, see http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/. 

Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Ads, you will continue to receive non-targeted ads.  Further, opting out of one or more NAI or DAA members only means that those selected members should no longer, under the DAA / NAI rules, deliver certain targeted ads to you.  This selective opting out will affect our websites and other services but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks).   
Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit this opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different device or web browser(s), or use a non-browser-based method of access (e.g., mobile app), your NAI / DAA browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective.  Mobile device opt-outs will not affect browser-based Interest-based Ads even on the same device, and you must opt-out separately for each device.

We are not responsible for the effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.  However, we support the ad industry’s 2009 Self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (<http://www.iab.net/media/file/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf>) and expect that ad networks we directly engage to serve you Interest-based Ads will do so as well, though we cannot guarantee their compliance.

**How to Disable Cookies**  
Some cookies are required for our website to function, as outlined above, and disabling them may prevent you from using certain aspects of our sites. However, to protect your privacy, you may choose to change your browser settings to disable non-essential cookies. The “Help” feature on most browsers provides instructions on how to prevent your browser from allowing new cookies and how to disable cookies. Please also use the following links for more information on how to manage popular browsers:

  * ###### [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en)

  * ###### [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US)

  * ###### [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)

  * ###### [Microsoft Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy)

  * ###### [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)

###### For more information regarding cookies, please see [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)  or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

  **_Sharing Personal Information_**  
American Campus Communities, Inc. is not in the business of selling personal information; however, certain circumstances may require us to share your information.

  **Service Providers and Storage of Information:** We use affiliates and third-party service providers to assist us in our business, and our websites may include functionality that allows certain kinds of interactions between our websites and a third-party website, platform, tool, application or other service, and access or display of third-party content via our websites (“Third Party Services”). These affiliates and third-party service providers collect personal information (such as eCommerce information) in connection with online payments, process payment transactions, facilitate communications, perform website analytics, utilize online targeted advertising and perform other services related to our business. Our affiliates may use your personal information for business planning purposes. Service providers are only permitted to use your information for their own purposes if that information is aggregated, statistical and de-identified, or if they have your consent.

  **Advertisers:** We share our customer data and website usage information about our visitors and applicants with selected third-parties for the purpose of targeting Internet advertisements on our websites and other websites that display our advertisements.  Read more about _Exercising Choices Regarding Analytics and Advertising_ above _._  
**Corporate restructuring:** If American Campus Communities enters into a business transaction with another party that involves the sale, transfer, or merger of all or a part of our business or involves granting security over all or part of our business, American Campus Communities may disclose your personal information to the other party for the purposes of the business transaction.

  **Law enforcement of legal requests:** We will disclose your personal information without your consent in response to a subpoena, warrant or order of a judicial or governmental authority with jurisdiction. We may also disclose your personal information in response to a lawful request from law enforcement officials or other governmental authorities or if we have reasonable grounds to believe that the information is relevant to a breach of contract or laws or in other cases where we are permitted to by law in connection with protecting our legal rights or those of others. 

  In matters involving a danger to personal or public safety, we may voluntarily provide information to appropriate government authorities.

  **_Security_**  
We are committed to online privacy and security. We have taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard your non-public personal information both during transmission and once it is in our possession. While our security measures are intended to protect your non-public personal information, the complete security of any transmission over the public internet cannot be guaranteed. As a result, we do not warrant the security of any electronically stored information or information you transmit to us over the Internet.

  **_How Long do we Keep your Personal Information?_**  
We keep your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, as may be required by law (e.g., for tax and accounting purposes), or as otherwise communicated to you. This is based on the nature of the data, why the data was collected and processed, and additional applicable legal retention requirements.

  **_Your California Privacy Rights_**  
We do not share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their own independent marketing purposes without your consent.  California residents may request the categories of personal information that we shared with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, if any.  Written requests may be sent to the following address:  

  American Campus Communities  
ATTN: Privacy Officer  
12700 Hill Country Blvd, Suite T-200  
Austin, TX 78738 

  You must write “Your California Privacy Rights” at the top of your inquiry.  We will respond to these requests within 30 days.  Requests that come to ACC by other means may result in a delayed response.  

  **How We Respond to Browser "Do Not Track" Signals**

  Some web browsers incorporate a "Do Not Track" feature that signals to websites you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. California law requires that website operators disclose how they respond to a Do Not Track signal and whether other third parties may collect personally identifiable information about an individual’s online activities from their site or service. We currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals. As the technology and communication between browser and website improves, we may make changes to our policy. Please refer to the sections titled “Personal Information We Collect Directly” and “Personal Information We Collect Indirectly” for additional information. 

  **_EEA Data Subject Rights_**  
Certain persons located in the EEA have the following rights, subject to certain exemptions, with respect to the personal information we hold:

  * ###### The right to request access to the personal data we hold;

  * ###### The right to request rectification of any inaccurate or incomplete personal data;

  * ###### The right to request the deletion or erasure of the personal data;

  * ###### The right to request that we restrict our processing of your personal data;

  * ###### The right to object to the processing of your personal data; and

  * ###### The right to request that your data be ported to another controller.

###### Additionally, when our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw this consent at any time. If you wish to exercise any of your rights above, please contact our Privacy Officer at [privacy@americancampus.com](mailto:privacy@americancampus.com?subject=American%20Campus%20Communities%20Privacy%20Policy).

  Our privacy team will review your request and respond as quickly as possible. If you are not satisfied with our answers to your questions, you also have the right to file a complaint with your supervisory authority.

  **_Personal Information from Children_**  
Because of the nature of our business, our services are not provided to minors. We will not ask minors, specifically children under the age of 13, to provide personal information.

  **_Privacy Policy Questions/Concerns_**  
If you have questions or concerns about your privacy or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

  American Campus Communities  
ATTN: Privacy Officer  
12700 Hill Country Blvd, Suite T-200  
Austin, TX 78738  
P: 512.732.1000

  You may also contact our Privacy Officer at [privacy@americancampus.com](mailto:privacy@americancampus.com?subject=American%20Campus%20Communities%20Privacy%20Policy).

  **_Changes to this Privacy Policy_**  
As our business changes, so will this privacy policy. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will let you know by posting the updated policy on this page and updating the policy’s “Effective Date” above.
